# DO, Van Quyet

Email: vqdo@connect.ust.hk

Homepage: https://dovanquyet.github.io/

## **Research Interests**

I always want to apply what I learned to real life. I am interested in applying AI in general and NLP in specific to various aspects of society, including mental healthcare and education. Nonetheless I need to research into a better design and training paradigm for LLMs. From now to the near future, with the emergence of LLMs, my research lies on the design of LLMs to enable cognitive functionality in the models.

### Education

## • M.Phil, Computer Science and Engineering

Aug 2022 - Present

Hong Kong University of Science and Technology (HKUST) Supervisor: Yangqiu Song (primary), Pascale Fung (co-) Specialization: Natural Language Processing, Data Mining

CGA: 4.0/4.3 as of Fall'22

#### • B.Sc, Data Science and Pure Math (Advanced)

Aug 2018 - Jun 2022

Hong Kong University of Science and Technology (HKUST)

CGA: 4.0/4.3 as of Graduation

First Class Honors with Academic Achievement Medal

## **Experience**

### • Software Engineer Assistant

Jun 2022 - Aug 2022

Eureka FinTech Limited, Hong Kong

- Work on the core (NLP) engine, including Data Crawling and Information Extraction

## • Research Assistant Sep 2021 - Jun 2022

HKUST Knowledge Computation Group, led by Prof. Yangqiu SONG

- Help to train and test Knowledge Models
- Propose, experiment ideas to populate Commonsense Knowledge Graph

## • AI Internee Mar 2021 - Sep 2021

Vietnam Technology International, Research and Development group

- Involved in projects in Computer Vision and Natural Language Processing (NLP), gained interest and specialty in NLP
- Key person of an internal project in Machine Translation, took part in almost all aspects of the project (in MLOps cycle)

#### **Awards and Honors**

- Academic Achievement Medalist of HKUST UG Class of 2022 [2022]
- HKUST Chern Class Achievement Scholarship with outstanding performance [2022]
- Awardees for the 16th, 17th HKUST Epsilon Fund Award [2021, 2022]
- Dean's List Student of HKUST [All semesters except Spring 2021]
- The Bronze Medal at the 58th International Mathematical Olympiad [2017]

#### Skills and Hobbies

- Technical: Python, PyTorch, familiar to TPU-training and Cloud Computing.
- Soft skills: Motivate others, work effectively under pressure and limited supervision.
- Organizational skills: Serve in the organizing committee of Vietnamese Student Association in Hong Kong.
- Language: Vietnamese (Native), English (proficient), Chinese (beginner).
- Hobbies: I like playing badminton, and especially love singing.

#### **Publications**

Remark: \* indicates equal contribution

#### 2023

• COLA: Contextualized Commonsense Causal Reasoning from the Causal Inference Perspective Zhaowei Wang, Quyet V. Do, Hongming Zhang, Jiayao Zhang, Weiqi Wang, Tianqing Fang, Yangqiu Song, Ginny Y. Wong, S. See

ACL 2023

- Introduce a new task of contextualized commonsense causal reasoning, with a new benchmark crowdsource-annotated dataset.
- Propose a theoretical framework and an implementation, namely COLA, to solve the task from the causal inference perspective
- CKBP v2: An Expert-Annotated Evaluation Set for Commonsense Knowledge Base Population Tianqing Fang\*, Quyet V. Do\*, Sehyun Choi, Weiqi Wang, Yangqiu Song Preprint, arXiv:2304.10392
  - Introduce a new expert-annotated evaluation set, that addresses the problems of its predecessor CKBP v1,
  - Conduct extensive experiments with state-of-the-art methods for CSKB Population and LLMs on the new evaluation set for future research comparisons
- A Multitask, Multilingual, Multimodal Evaluation of ChatGPT on Reasoning, Hallucination, and Interactivity

Yejin Bang, Samuel Cahyawijaya, Nayeon Lee, Wenliang Dai, Dan Su, Bryan Wilie, Holy Lovenia, Ziwei Ji, Tiezheng Yu, Willy Chung, **Quyet V. Do**, Yan Xu, Pascale Fung

Preprint, arXiv:2302.04023

- Extensive empirical evaluation of ChatGPT, focus on three topics: reasoning, hallucination, and interactivity,
- Discuss the future direction to improve ChatGPT and other LLMs

#### 2022

• PseudoReasoner: Leveraging Pseudo Labels for Commonsense Knowledge Base Population

Tianqing Fang, **Quyet V. Do**, Hongming Zhang, Yangqiu Song, Ginny Y. Wong and Simon See *Findings of EMNLP 2022* 

- Use the idea of pseudo labels to perform semi-supervised learning on CSKB Population,
- Propose a filtering strategy for pseudo labels using influence function and self distillation (the student model's own predictions)